Improve Action Settings
Welcome back to this session on value creation.
And now we're down to the fifth step and the sixth step.
And recall, I want to realize my gains.
We looked at recognizing value needs, defining the change opportunity,
measuring existing conditions, and analyzing contributing forces.
In other words, we looked at the conditional forces
that are in place, that define the opportunities to change.
That if I can put them in a positive direction. Then I can close the gap.
I can make the gap go away. I want to reinforce that.
By finding the forces that will move me in a positive direction,
I can then close that gap.
And thereby satisfy the need.
Now the next step in doing that is to improve the action settings of each of the forces.
So, recall from last time, where we took a look at those forces.
Right here. We selected the ones we're going to go operate on.
Now, if I take one of those forces.
Again, I’m going to use the example of the dog. There's the T-bar and there's the time.
It's a strong force, let's say. And I pick that one.
So, now I gotta define the settings of that force.
In other words, I want to go back and define
the goal. See, now is when I define the goal.
I come back, measure existing conditions. If I didn't define the goal at that point. Now I do.
There's two ways to do it. I can predefine the goal.
Or I can wait till I get down to here to do that.
So, as before. I want us to sit here, take a quick look,
at the three words associated with this step.
Which is called improve action
settings.
Now, what's a setting. A setting is merely a setting.
It's a position that we put it to. For example, when you go in and adjust your thermostat.
You take the knob and twist it. You change the setting.
From maybe 75 degrees to 80 degrees.
You change the setting of the variable called temperature.
Well, that's an action setting. And you got to improve it.
So basically, for that condition that we gave the example with the dog,
right here, time of day. We need to change it from 8 o'clock setting.
Remember, the original setting was 8 o’clock AM. This was the is setting.
The is setting. We need to change it
6 o'clock in the morning ought setting.
That’s an action setting.
In other words, I need to take action on time.
On the variable called, time the newspaper is delivered. See.
Take action on that. Create a new action setting.
Create a new ought condition, which is 6 o'clock in the morning. Change it from 8 to 6.
See, change the settings. That's one of the conditions.
That if I change that condition
and I change the settings of the other key conditions that I selected.
Remember that I selected several key conditions.
Of which time newspaper delivered was just one. If I change it to those new settings,
then what's gonna happen?
What's gonna happen is Y is a function of X is going to play out.
All those settings is going to come over here and have an impact on Y. See.
And what’s that going to do? That’s going to come back and close the gap.
That’s going to make that gap get smaller. It’s gonna close it down.
That's going to increase my value.
Now, that in essence, is the value creation process.
Thank you for choosing SSMI.